export default {
  id: 'low_1006_6_2a',
  name: '상용한자(6학년-2/음독찾기)',
  data: [
    { question: '沿', answer: ['물 따라갈 연', 'そう', 'えん'] },
    { question: '映', answer: ['비칠 영', 'うつ(る)、うつ(す)、は(える)', 'えい'] },
    { question: '染', answer: ['물들 염', 'そ(める)、そ(まる)、し(みる)、し(み)', 'せん'] },
    { question: '誤', answer: ['그르칠 오', 'あやま(る)', 'ご'] },
    { question: '欲', answer: ['하고자할 욕', 'ほっ(する)、ほ(しい)', 'よく'] },
    { question: '宇', answer: ['집 우', '집', 'う'] },
    { question: '郵', answer: ['우편 우', '우편', 'ゆう'] },
    { question: '優', answer: ['넉넉할 우', 'やさ(しい)、すぐ(れる)', 'ゆう'] },
    { question: '源', answer: ['근원 원', 'みなもと', 'げん'] },
    { question: '危', answer: ['위태할 위', 'あぶ(ない)、あや(うい)、あや(ぶむ)', 'き'] },
    { question: '乳', answer: ['젖 유', 'ちち、ち', 'にゅう'] },
    { question: '幼', answer: ['어릴 유', 'おさな(い)', 'よう'] },
    { question: '遺', answer: ['남길 유', '남길', 'い、ゆい'] },
    { question: '疑', answer: ['의심할 의', 'うたが(う)', 'ぎ'] },
    { question: '異', answer: ['다를 이', 'こと(なる)', 'い'] },
    { question: '翌', answer: ['다음날 익', '다음날', 'よく'] },
    { question: '認', answer: ['알 인', 'みと(める)', 'にん'] },
    { question: '仁', answer: ['어질 인', '어질', 'じん、に'] },
    { question: '賃', answer: ['품삯 임', '품삯', 'ちん'] },
    { question: '姿', answer: ['모양 자', 'すがた', 'し'] },
    { question: '磁', answer: ['자석 자', '자석', 'じ'] },
    { question: '蚕', answer: ['누에 잠', 'かいこ', 'さん'] },
    { question: '将', answer: ['장수 장', '장수', 'しょう'] },
    { question: '装', answer: ['꾸밀 장', 'よそお(う)', 'そう、しょう'] },
    { question: '蔵', answer: ['감출 장', 'くら', 'ぞう'] },
    { question: '臓', answer: ['오장 장', '오장', 'ぞう'] },
    { question: '障', answer: ['막을 장', 'さわ(る)', 'しょう'] },
    { question: '裁', answer: ['마를 재', 'た(つ)、さば(く)', 'さい'] },
    { question: '著', answer: ['나타날 저', 'あらわ(す)、いちじる(しい)', 'ちょ'] },
    { question: '専', answer: ['오로지 전', 'もっぱ(ら)', 'せん'] },
    { question: '展', answer: ['펼 전', '펼', 'てん'] },
    { question: '頂', answer: ['정수리 정', 'いただ(く)、いただき', 'ちょう'] },
    { question: '済', answer: ['건널 제', 'す(む)、す(ます)', 'さい'] },
    { question: '諸', answer: ['모두 제', '모두', 'しょ'] },
    { question: '除', answer: ['덜 제', 'のぞ(く)', 'じょ、じ'] },
    { question: '操', answer: ['잡을 조', 'みさお、あやつ(る)', 'そう'] },
    { question: '潮', answer: ['밀물 조', 'しお', 'ちょう'] },
    { question: '存', answer: ['있을 존', '있을', 'そん、ぞん'] },
    { question: '尊', answer: ['높을 존', 'とうと(い)、とうと(ぶ)、たっと(い)、たっと(ぶ)', 'そん'] },
    { question: '宗', answer: ['마루 종', '마루', 'しゅう、そう'] },
    { question: '従', answer: ['좇을 종', 'したが(う)、したが(える)', 'じゅう、しょう、じゅ'] },
    { question: '縦', answer: ['세로 종', 'たて', 'じゅう'] },
    { question: '座', answer: ['자리 좌', 'すわ(る)', 'ざ'] },
    { question: '宙', answer: ['집 주', '집', 'ちゅう'] },
    { question: '株', answer: ['그루 주', 'かぶ', 'しゅ'] },
    { question: '奏', answer: ['아뢸 주', 'かな(でる)', 'そう'] },
    { question: '衆', answer: ['무리 중', '무리', 'しゅう、しゅ'] },
    { question: '蒸', answer: ['찔 증', 'む(す)、む(れる)、む(らす)', 'じょう'] },
    { question: '誌', answer: ['기록할 지', '기록할', 'し'] },
    { question: '至', answer: ['이를 지', 'いた(る)', 'し'] },
    { question: '窓', answer: ['창 창', 'まど', 'そう'] },
    { question: '創', answer: ['비롯할 창', '비롯할', 'そう'] },
    { question: '冊', answer: ['책 책', '책', 'さつ、さく'] },
    { question: '策', answer: ['꾀 책', '꾀', 'さく'] },
    { question: '処', answer: ['곳 처', '곳', 'しょ'] },
    { question: '尺', answer: ['자 척', '자', 'しゃく'] },
    { question: '泉', answer: ['샘 천', 'いずみ', 'せん'] },
    { question: '庁', answer: ['관청 청', '관청', 'ちょう'] },
    { question: '寸', answer: ['마디 촌', '마디', 'すん'] },
    { question: '推', answer: ['밀 추', 'お(す)', 'すい'] },
    { question: '縮', answer: ['줄일 축', 'ちぢ(む)、ちぢ(まる)、ちぢ(める)、ちぢ(れる)、ちぢ(らす)', 'しゅく'] },
    { question: '忠', answer: ['충성 충', '충성', 'ちゅう'] },
    { question: '就', answer: ['나아갈 취', 'つ(く)、つ(ける)', 'しゅう、じゅ'] },
    { question: '層', answer: ['층 층', '층', 'そう'] },
    { question: '値', answer: ['값 치', 'ね、あたい', 'ち'] },
    { question: '針', answer: ['바늘 침', 'はり', 'しん'] },
    { question: '宅', answer: ['집 택/댁 댁', '집', 'たく'] },
    { question: '誕', answer: ['낳을 탄', '낳을', 'たん'] },
    { question: '探', answer: ['찾을 탐', 'さ(ぐる)、さ(がす)', 'たん'] },
    { question: '討', answer: ['칠 토', 'うつ', 'とう'] },
    { question: '痛', answer: ['아플 통', 'いた(い)、いた(む)、いた(める)', 'つう'] },
    { question: '派', answer: ['갈래 파', '갈래', 'は'] },
    { question: '片', answer: ['조각 편', 'かた', 'へん'] },
    { question: '肺', answer: ['허파 폐', '허파', 'はい'] },
    { question: '陛', answer: ['대궐섬돌 폐', '대궐섬돌', 'へい'] },
    { question: '閉', answer: ['닫을 폐', 'し(まる)、し(める)、と(じる)、と(ざす)', 'へい'] },
    { question: '割', answer: ['벨 할', 'わ(る)、わり、わ(れる)、さ(く)', 'かつ'] },
    { question: '郷', answer: ['시골 향', '시골', 'きょう、ごう'] },
    { question: '憲', answer: ['법 헌', '법', 'けん'] },
    { question: '革', answer: ['가죽 혁', 'かわ', 'かく'] },
    { question: '穴', answer: ['구멍 혈', 'あな', 'けつ'] },
    { question: '呼', answer: ['부를 호', 'よ(ぶ)', 'こ'] },
    { question: '紅', answer: ['붉을 홍', 'べに、くれない', 'こう、く'] },
    { question: '拡', answer: ['넓힐 확', '넓힐', 'かく'] },
    { question: '皇', answer: ['임금 황', '임금', 'こう、おう'] },
    { question: '灰', answer: ['재 회', 'はい', 'かい'] },
    { question: '孝', answer: ['효도 효', '효도', 'こう'] },
    { question: '后', answer: ['임금 후', 'きさき', 'こう'] },
    { question: '揮', answer: ['휘두를 휘', '휘두를', 'き'] },
    { question: '胸', answer: ['가슴 흉', 'むね、むな', 'きょう'] },
    { question: '吸', answer: ['마실 흡', 'す(う)', 'きゅう'] }
  ]
}
